S N E H A

CONTACT INFO

E-mail sneha29shukla@gmail.com

Phone +91 9008388393

Address A-604, Meenakshi Classic Apartments, 27th Main Road,

HSR Layout, Sector 1, Bangalore, Karnataka

LinkedIn sneha29shukla

Github snehashukla29

ABOUT ME

Senior software engineer with almost 10 years of experience working on scalable architectures, distributed computing, data analytics, and microservices on cloud infrastructures. Formerly obtained a Masters in Computer Science with specialization in Information Security from Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

2014-2022

Flipkart Internet Private Limited | Bangalore, India

- Led a team which built ML solutions at scale for Flipkart's user personalization charter.
- Part of the team which built a scalable solution for building real time and batch data pipelines to be used to train ML models.
- Part of the team building tools for the Data Science team at Flipkart. This
 included solutions for serving predictions in real time at scale, ensuring
 reproductibility of experiments and scheduled retraining of ML models.
- Part of the core team re-architecting the legacy framework supporting warehouse processes and inventory management.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2012-2014

Infoedge Technologies Pvt Ltd | Delhi NCR, India

- Built the end to end password (and PII) encryption system for Naukri as part of my research paper for Masters. The final implementation was used by other sister organizations, including NaukriGulf.
- Part of the team that built a XML based Data Manipulation Language to standardise all microservice calls in a single format across Naukri.

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science with specialization in Information Security

2010-2012

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology | Delhi, India

- Amongst top 5 students in the graduating class
- Vice President and Treasurer, ACM Student Chapter
- Research Paper topic: "Design, Review and Implementation of Password hashing and Security Policy at Naukri.com"

B.Tech in Information Technology

2006-2010

Dronacharya College of Engineering, Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University | Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh

• Best Student of B.Tech (2010) for all-round performance

ACHIEVEMENTS

Open Source Contribution

2017

Contributions to Aesop (Flipkart's in-house solution for chain events relay)

Flipkart Machine Learning Challenge

2019

• Top 5 among 52 teams

INDUSTRY TALKS

YOU ARE WHO YOU SHOP FOR

2018

Al For India - Flagship Tech Conference by Flipkart | Bangalore, India

 Presented this talk as a lead developer. This talk went into the details of the "Behavioral Demography" project at Flipkart as part of the personalization charter.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Building end to end engineering solutions for complex use cases
- Researching and evaluating design choices and existing solutions to find best fit for a given problem
- Writing High and Low level Design Documents (HLD/LLD)
- Conducting HLD/LLD/Code reviews
- Technical mentoring of team and task breakdowns for large projects

Programming Languages Java, Scala, Python

Frameworks

Airflow, Docker, K8s, Istio, Apache Spark, Apache MapReduce, Hadoop, Kafka, Spring, Pytorch, Keras,

Storage Technologies

Hbase, Mysql, Couchbase, Aerospike, Hazelcast

Cou	ır	S	e	s
Tak	e	n		

- Foundations of Computer Security
- Applied Cryptography
- Topics in Computer Security
- Ethical Hacking
- Digital and Cyber Forensics
- Research Methods
- Distributed Systems
- Information Retrieval
- Advanced Algorithms

Languages

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Hindi (native)

REFERENCES

On Request